[Music]
let's talk
money hello and welcome to let's talk
money I'm your host Sur upadhi it's the
middle of December which means it's
holiday season now many of you would
have already planned your travel and
vacations and those who haven't are
probably looking forward to booking
their first trip of 2025 early in the
New Year yes the travel bug has bitten
us all and perhaps here to stay so how
can we plan smarter for our travels and
our holidays what are the hottest
destinations of 2025 and while we
research enough on the hotels and the
experiences that we want on that dream
trip do we pay enough attention to
travel insurance yes you got it it is a
travel special edition of let's talk
money and helping us plan our 2025 wust
better our moit Joi of Skyscanner and
Priya deshmuk of IC Lombard lady and
gentlemen great to have both of you on
the show thank you very much for joining
in and I'm I don't know if both of you
have booked your trips or if you're big
travel Enthusiast yourself moit Mo
joining us all the way from London this
morning
right yes hi good morning good morning
lovely to see you all Pria what about
you are you a big Avid traveler yourself
well I do travel and uh thank you for
having me on the show and uh you know
good morning to everybody all right uh
so you know we want to start with some
broad brush trends of uh you know what
the qualitative and quantitative aspects
tell us yes we know our friends our
family everyone's traveling more but
moit you tell us I mean you guys on
Skyscanner you're looking at all of
these searches all of these bookings uh
day in and day out so what has
2024 uh brought forward when it comes to
Indians
traveling yeah it's an exciting time for
travel at the moment 2024 was all about
cultural exploration so we saw a shift
in the Indian traveler mindset moving
from just going to a new country to
escape to actually going there to
immerse themselves in the culture right
from Geek tripping which is going to see
your favorite artists perform somewhere
to actually going to some iconic
landmarks that they've seen on a TV show
so we've SE seen that shift in 2024 and
moving on to 2025 the desire for travel
remains uh really strong um 86% of
Indian Travelers want to spend the same
or more um on flights and 80% of Indian
Travelers want to spend the same or more
on hotels which shows there is a big big
um interest in travel for next year
we've also seen um some travel trends
that have come out through some number
crunching that we've done through a
survey that we've done um and then we've
highlighted seven travel Trends one of
them being sport mode which is
essentially traveling to see your
favorite athlete or to support your
favorite team we also looked at Art
Venture where there is a big focus on um
Indian Travelers wanting to go and
experience immersive art um reset
jetters which is another one which is
all about Wellness based traveling
taking some time off to disconnect that
continues from 2024 into
2025 and and then there are a few more
which talk about Astro Adventures which
is wanting to go and see the aurora
borealis the northern lights and promo
in Norway has come out as one of the
trending destinations where you can go
and and see them and then there are a
few like gamey vacation we've seen a lot
of interest from Indian Travelers
wanting to go to location that they'
either played on a game or it also kind
of reflects on some esport events that
they want to go for and the last couple
being Horticulture um which is wanting
to um experience the the the cherry
blossom
and last the cowboy core which is just
having an experience of a farmhouse day
so that's the various travel Trends
we've seen going into 20125 and and if
if you talk just about 2024 um for
December itself we've seen the top
searches for people Indian Travelers
wanting to travel have been Goa bagdogra
Kochi Dubai and almati these are the
destination from December my God I'm
already getting major foro moit because
of all the trends that you described
from from the cherry blossoms to the
northern lights and so on and so forth
to the wellness retreats we want to do
them all right actually not one we want
to do as many as possible in every given
year but then B budgets are finite so we
have to work with what we have I'll come
back on some of the individual Trends in
in just a bit but Priya you tell us now
clearly all this is happening but what
about from when you see it through a
financial lens has it meant uh You Know
Better Business for you as well when it
comes to the travel insurance segment
absolutely and um you know quite frankly
I'm quite fascinated to hear what moit
said and you know you have an example in
me who's traveled to Japan just for the
cherry blossoms and uh it's amazing to
see what's happening across the globe
and how the travel Trends and tourism is
coming back we have around 15 million uh
Indian Nationals who have traveled in
the first half of 2024 and we expect um
you know total 80 um you know million uh
traveling throughout the year of 2024 so
travel uh trend is back uh we did see
some slow down uh during the co season
postco it is come back with great um you
know amazing progress and alongside the
travel season and people going for
experiential uh you know kind of uh
travel uh destinations and all the you
know fancy names that M mentioned uh
even the insurance sector the financial
insurance sector has moved that along
the side in the curve of how people have
chosen destinations and travel uh you
know kind of uh planning and it's it's
really uh fascinating to see how the
growth has happened there's uh a kager
of around 14% that we've observed and uh
by 20 2040 uh we're seeing a you know
explosive growth of almost 50% of the
total travel tourism Insurance uh that's
going to come our way so the travel
insurance industry seems to be growing
at these big numbers 40 50% because of
the the boom and Trav it's a reflection
of how people are choosing uh to travel
U uh internationally as well as
domestically so Priya I mean just a
question on um the trends from this year
now travel insurance t to be a very
minuscule percentage of the overall trip
cost right probably 0 1% uh so in terms
of the premium Trends in 24 what have we
seen so far are premiums going up going
down what should we expect well um you
know when you talk about a travel
product uh you know while it's a
minuscule of the cost of the total
travel planning that a consumer would do
uh it will all depend on the you know
country the duration of stay uh you know
what kind of um you know stay plan that
you have and you know features of uh you
know are you going for a Adventure Sport
kind of an activity so it will all
depend on that but with the growing
volume of uh business and uh the way the
penetration is increasing and more and
more people are being aware because of
two reasons one uh the treatment cost u
mean locations or you know destinations
that people are traveling as well as uh
you know the Peace of Mind typically um
you know 50,000 USD some insured for a
aged uh uh customer of around 50 years
would uh the premium would range around
uh 10,000 odd rupees for a gold plan and
a more comprehensive and very very uh uh
you know all-inclusive program would
cost around 15,000 OD so that's quite uh
the range in which you would see the um
you know travel insurance products being
fair enough so so they're not sort of
shooting through the roof we're not
expecting a very huge surge in travel
premiums right that's good to hear I'll
come back on it in in just a bit but
moit uh again to talk about the trends
and the costing part uh now people are
traveling irrespective of the cost but
the fact is that costs are going up
right you look at flights to Europe in
throughout 2024 I remember I mean preo I
took a flight to one of my dream
destinations in Europe for some you know
50k for a return return ticket and now
that number is going to what 75,000
880,000 so in terms of just cost for
this uh the sort of international travel
what are we in for in
2025 yeah it's a really good point um
cost of living is still top of mind for
Indian Travelers like um Indian
Travelers prioritize the cost of flights
cost of hotels even the cost of food of
the destination that they're going for
but having said that the rising middle
class and the increase in travel spend
that individuals have now and also Visa
access becoming um slightly easier in
many of the locations continues to to
drive the interest among Indian
Travelers an interesting fact we also
found out was 66% of Indian Travelers
are planning to travel more in 2025 so
that shows that although cost is top of
mind they want to continue to travel
into the new year and having said that
what we are seeing is um Airlines
increasing their networks um there's a
lot of like domestic there's a lot of
low value lowcost Airlines having
competition and because of this
additional networks to different
destination what we'll see in 2025 is
the prices stabilizing further and and
and to meet the demand of uh of Indian
Travelers we expect more routs to to
start beginning which will also
stabilize the prices further that sounds
really good actually you know what um M
we're playing a graphic right now from
your report that uh highlights some of
the maybe most wallet friendly or budget
friendly destinations for 2025 yeah
we've got them on the screen now Oslo
London Doha uh there's Soul there's Baku
where there's a slight drop and there's
kazakistan where there's a big drop
actually 44% drop in airfares can you
tell us a little more about it I mean
this is what average of how many months
and can we project this into the new
year we all want to believe that yes
airfares are not going to go through the
roof so what are the destinations to
look at yeah those numbers are very
exciting for us as well that is why we
wanted to highlight them to our Indian
Travelers like seeing almati in
kazakistan having that 44% reduction in
price year on year over 12 months um is
really exciting because uh it it shows
that Indian Travelers want to go and
experience the culture which takes back
to to the point I mentioned about
cultural exploration it's also about
going to destinations which are more
pocket friendly and stronger rupee plays
uh quite important um in in in this and
and we also see the the Visa access
which is becoming easier for Indians to
traveling to these destinations and
because of that the airlines are having
more networks um to these roots and
because of that we see the average fair
prices dropping significantly and you
see almati in kazakistan known for his
culture and and and and really good
Landscapes we also saw um Jakarta in
Indonesia which is which is a wellness
Retreat we see some some really stunning
beaches there as well same with
Singapore it's getting popular um every
year because of what it offers to the
Indian
Travelers very very interesting so M
before we let you go uh you know give us
more hope I you guys have done our top
destinations list as well I think and I
was very proud to see I think shalong
features on that list of top
destinations of 2025 right so tell us
how you compile that list and uh you
know any hacks any tips for better
planning more sort of budget friendly
planning how can we have happier
holidays in
2025 yeah I was really excited to see um
shilong as the number one destination
for Indian Travelers in terms of
searches so what we saw in terms of the
the data crunching we did was um which
destination has seen an increase in
searches compared to the previous year
and shilong saw a tremendous increase of
over
800% um for Indian Travelers um shilong
also known as the the Scotland of the
East um pristine legs beautiful
landscapes easy access obviously no Visa
issues for us Indian Travelers so I
wasn't surprised to finally have an
Indian city on that list Baku continues
to be um um really strong in the top 10
at number two um which gives you an
affordable European experience and easy
to get to as well and easy Visa access
um tromo in Norway also makes uh the top
10 of the list which is known for going
seeing Northern Lights and Aurora
Borealis and then you can see tashkin in
usbekistan also known for his culture
and and Beauty that's drawing Indian
Travelers so these are uh the different
uh destinations we've seen based on what
Indian Travelers have been searching on
the Skyscanner website and app so how
many of them have you covered moit and
which ones are you heading to in the New
Year definitely tashkin in usbekistan is
on my U goto list for sure uh
unfortunately I haven't been to shilong
as well so shilong should be there in my
number one list as well so can't wait to
cover both shilong and tashen very soon
fantastic well we wish you good luck
with that plan and thank you very much
for joining in this gives us plenty of
food for thought and uh you know plenty
to think and plan about and get excited
about in the new New Year travel always
top of mine thank you very much for
giving us The Skys scanner
perspective thank you so much all right
well with that we have to take a very
quick break we'll come back on the other
side and now that we know which are the
hottest destinations to get to the
question is you need to pay a lot of
focus and attention to the travel
insurance part it's more than just a
quick checklist before you're heading to
the airport we'll tell you why uh priia
will give us more details on this in
just a bit
[Music]
let's talk money